osclass.org 2019-09-10

# Privacy policy - Osclass, the free classifieds script

OSCLASS SL makes available all additional information related to their handling of your personal data, as established by applicable regulations—REGULATION (UE) 2016/679 OF THE EUROPEAN PARLIAMENT AND OF THE COUNCIL of 27 April 2016 (GDPR). In this respect, in agreement with OSCLASS SL’s data protection policy—which uses a layer/level-based information model—we gather all the additional information (Level 2), where basic information is shown in detail related to our processing of data that you must be aware of.

Person in charge:  
Identity: OSCLASS SL   
Address: Carrer de Can Bruixa, 16, 08028 Barcelona  
Data Protection Delegate: datos@osclass.org

### For what purposes do we use your personal data?

At Osclass we process the information provided by interested individuals with the following purposes:

  * a) Sending technical support emails to individuals who use our software. 
  * b) Advertising and commercial research activities for our own products and services through different means and channels of communication, such as our newsletter. We will use the following means in order to reach you with remote sales deals, advertisements, promotions and free samples of our services and/or products: postal mail, email, SMS, telephone, mobile applications, and opinion surveys.
  * c) Answering your requests and questions related to our website.
  * d) We keeps a list of domains that use our software for statistical purposes.

### How have we obtained your data?

Personal data used by the Company come directly from interested individuals through the forms enabled by the Company.

### How long do we keep your data?

We will keep your personal data for as long as you use our website and do not request that we delete your data. In some cases, we may keep personal data that could prove your management of our services and the exercise of your rights.

Additionally, the Company carries out regular analysis of data retention periods, deleting data out of the Company’s own initiative for considering that information as obsolete or outdated.

### What is the legitimation for processing your data?

The legal basis for processing your data is the consent you have granted as you filled out any of the forms provided by our Company. Commercial research of our own products and services, as well as those belonging to third parties, is based on consent. Still, in no case will withdrawing consent for our own or third parties’ commercial research condition your status as a registered user.

### Who will be the recipients of your data?

Data processing for promotional and commercial research purposes may involve handing your data to third parties belonging to sectors specified under the Purposes section.

Certain service providers may also have access to your data. These companies will only be able to access data for the sole purpose of providing the contracted service, following the Company’s instructions and without them being able to use your data for any other purpose. All providers subscribe to confidentiality pledges regarding the use of the information to which they have access due to their provided services, in accordance with current regulation.

### What are your rights when you provide your data to us?

Any individual has the right to request access to their personal data, a rectification or deletion of their personal data, a restriction of their use, or to object to their use, as well as the right to data portability or the right to withdraw consent on any particular purpose. To this end, individuals may send a letter to Osclass SL, at Carrer Can Bruixa, 16, Bajos, 08028, Barcelona, Spain, or send an email at datos@osclass.org mentioning the right they would like to exercise. Applicants must attach a proof of identity, such as a photocopy of their ID card.

Furthermore, note that you have the right to file a claim before the appropriate control authority—the Spanish Data Protection Agency, or Agencia Española de Protección de Datos—if you believe there has been any kind of infringement in relation to the processing of your personal data.

In the event a data processing restriction is requested, we will only keep the data for the purpose of exercising or defending against claims; in the case a user objects to it, data will cease to be processed, except for compelling, legitimate reasons, or the exercise or defense against eventual claims.

### We appreciate your cooperation

At Osclass we try to control—to the extent of our possibilities—the appropriate use of the personal data we are responsible for on behalf of third parties to whom we may have had to provide such information. For this reason, we ask that, in the event you become aware or have a reasonable suspicion that any of our providers listed in the [Cookies section](https://osclass.org/page/cookies) is making improper use of your personal information, you would notify us promptly so that we can take relevant measures in order to proceed with this issue.

Likewise, to ensure the data we have are correct and up-to-date, we ask that you notify us as soon as possible about any change in your data, or if, for any reason, you discover that we have any incorrect information about you, so that we can proceed with the appropriate rectification.

OSCLASS SL, pone a su disposición la información adicional concerniente al tratamiento de sus datos personales, tal y como establece la normativa en la materia: REGLAMENTO (UE) 2016/679 DEL PARLAMENTO EUROPEO Y DEL CONSEJO de 27 de abril de 2016 (RGPD). En este sentido y alineado con la política de protección de datos de OSCLASS SL basada en el modelo de información por capas o niveles, a continuación, recogemos la información adicional (segundo nivel) donde se presenta con detalle la información básica relativa al tratamiento de datos que debe conocer.

Datos del Responsable:  
Identidad: OSCLASS SL  
Domicilio: Carrer de Can Bruixa, 16, 08028 Barcelona  
Delegado de Protección de Datos: datos@osclass.org 

### ¿Con qué finalidad tratamos sus datos personales?

En Osclass tratamos la información que nos facilitan las personas interesadas de acuerdo con las siguientes finalidades:

  * a) Envío de mail de soporte a los usuarios del nuestro software
  * b) Actividades de publicidad y prospección comercial por distintos medios y canales de comunicación de productos y servicios propios, como nuestra newsletter. Le podremos ofrecer, por cualquiera de los medios siguientes: correo postal, correo electrónico, SMS, teléfono, aplicaciones móviles y, encuestas de opinión, ofertas de venta a distancia, publicidad, promociones y muestras gratuitas de nuestros servicios y/o productos.
  * c) Atender sus solicitudes y consultas relacionadas con el Portal.
  * d) Guardamos un listado de dominios que utilizan nuestro software para propóstios estadísticos.

### ¿Cómo hemos obtenido sus datos?

Los datos personales tratados por la Empresa proceden directamente de los interesados a través de los formularios habilitados por la Empresa.

### ¿Por cuánto tiempo conservamos sus datos?

Los datos personales se conservarán mientras ud sea usuario y no solicite la supresión de sus datos. En algún caso podrán conservarse los datos personales que puedan probar la gestión de los servicios y el ejercicio de sus derechos.

Asimismo, la Empresa lleva a cabo periódicamente un análisis de los periodos de conservación de los datos, eliminando los datos de oficio por considerar que la información haya quedado obsoleta o desactualizada.

### ¿Cuál es la legitimación para el tratamiento de sus datos?

La base legal para el tratamiento de sus datos se basa en el consentimiento otorgado al completar cualquiera de los formularios que dispone la Empresa.

La oferta prospectiva de productos y servicios propios o de terceros está basada en el consentimiento, sin que en ningún caso la retirada del consentimiento para prospección comercial propia o de terceros condicione, en su caso, su situación como usuario registrado.

### ¿A qué destinatarios se comunicarán sus datos?

La realización de tratamientos con fines de publicidad y prospección comercial podrá implicar la entrega de sus datos a terceras entidades de los sectores especificados en el apartado de finalidades.

También tendrán acceso determinadas empresas prestadoras de servicios. Estos proveedores sólo podrán acceder a los datos con el único objeto de prestar el servicio contratado, siguiendo las instrucciones de la Empresa y sin que puedan destinarlos para ninguna otra finalidad. Todos los proveedores suscriben compromisos de confidencialidad en el uso de la información a la que acceden por su servicio de conformidad con la normativa vigente.

### ¿Cuáles son sus derechos cuando nos facilita sus datos?

Cualquier persona tiene el derecho a solicitar el acceso a sus datos personales, su rectificación o supresión, o la limitación de su tratamiento, o a oponerse al tratamiento, así como el derecho a la portabilidad de los datos. Así como el derecho a retirar el consentimiento en cualquiera de sus finalidades. Para ello puede dirigir una carta a OSclass SL., la dirección Carrer Can Bruixa, 16, bajos, 08028, Barcelona, España o remitiendo un correo electrónico datos@osclass.org indicando el derecho que deseas ejercer. Deberá acreditarse la identidad del solicitante, por ejemplo acompañando fotocopia del DNI.

Asimismo, le informamos de que tiene derecho a presentar una reclamación ante la autoridad de control competente (Agencia Española de Protección de Datos), si considera que se ha producido algún tipo de vulneración en relación con el tratamiento de sus datos personales.

En el caso que se solicite la limitación del tratamiento de sus datos únicamente los conservaremos para el ejercicio o la defensa de reclamaciones y en los casos de oposición dejarán de tratarse los datos, salvo por motivos legítimos imperiosos, o el ejercicio o la defensa de posibles reclamaciones.

### Valoramos su colaboración

En Osclass procuramos controlar, dentro de nuestras posibilidades, el uso correcto de los datos personales de los que somos responsables por parte de terceros a quienes se los hayamos tenido que facilitar. Por tal motivo le solicitamos que, en caso de que tenga conocimiento o sospecha de que cualquiera de nuestros proveedores, antes indicados, está haciendo un uso indebido de su información personal, nos lo notifique sin dilación para poder adoptar las acciones pertinentes que proceda llevar a cabo.

Asimismo, para garantizar que los datos que tenemos son correctos y se encuentran actualizados, le rogamos que, si se produce alguna modificación en sus datos, o si, por cualquier motivo, detecta que tenemos algún dato suyo incorrecto, nos lo comunique a la mayor brevedad para proceder a la oportuna subsanación.
